# Matthew A.Cottrell

ClassicCottrell.ca

ClassicCottrell@gmail.com

778-232-4629



My name is Matt and I'm a UI/UX designer. I've been in the software industry for 5 years. When I'm not at work, I'm either involved in film production, drawing weird cartoon characters, or reminiscing about my printing days, when I had access to a vinyl plotter, huge screens and endless rolls of paper.



## **Experience**

- 5 years in a start-up environment
- Outgoing & positive personality
- Enthusiastic & dedicated learner
- Adapts easily to new situations & people
- I work well independently, however, I love working in a team environment & brainstorming with my colleagues.

## **Work History**

## Tagga - Creative Lead current

## UX/UI Lead 2016 - 2017

- User stories, Site mapping, Conception of new platform tools
- Creation of Low Fidelity to High Fidelity designs through wireframes, sketches, design, mockups, prototyping (pencil paper, adobe XD)
- Software theme & branding, element styles (color exploration, fonts, icons)

## Lead Design 2011-2016

- Cross Channel Campaign Strategy
- Design & creation of media for campaigns (in-store print design, facebook/

Instagram/twitter social posts, and responsive websites)

- Front End Development and QA for site deployments
- Social Community Creation
- Social posting and storytelling

#### Intern

2011 - 2011

- Video production
- Print preparation

## C2 Imaging

2000 - 2010

- Sign Maker
- Large Format Digital Print Operator
- Lün Cutter Press Operator
- Saturn 5 Colour Printing Press Assistant

#### **Education and Training**

BCIT - New Media Design & Web Development Certificate2010 - 2011Vancouver Film School - Foundation in Film & Design2006 - 2007Langley Fine Arts School - Fine Arts Major2001 - 2004

## Skills

#### UI/UX Design & Coding Skills

- HTML, CSS Strong knowledge
- Foundation, SASS, LESS
- Responsive design
- Email template creation
- Campaign Monitor & MailChimp
- Facebook Ad Manager
- Google Adwords
- Adobe XD

#### Art & Design Skills

- Adobe Creative suite (photoshop, illustrator, indesign, experience design)
- Video Final Cut & After Effects
- Lighting & Set Design
- Classical 2D Animation
- Stop Motion & Cinemagraphs GIF's

## **Print & Layout Skills**

- Sign maker (layout and quality control)
- 5 color printing process
- T-shirt printing process
- Store Front vinyl sign application
- Zün (digital die-cutting)
- Prepress knowledge & understanding